[
{
      "question":"Which Buddhist council was held during the reign of Kanishka?",
      "optionA":"1st",
      "optionB":"2nd",
      "optionC":"3rd",
      "optionD":"4th",
      "correctAns":"4th"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following place of Andhra Pradesh is well known for a Buddhist Stupa?",
      "optionA":"Amaravati",
      "optionB":"Srikakulam",
      "optionC":"Rajahmundry",
      "optionD":"Chitoor",
      "correctAns":"Amaravati"
   },
   {
      "question":"The three sangams were organized under the chairmanship of which of the following?",
      "optionA":"Rishi Agastya, Nakkirar, Rishi Agastya",
      "optionB":"Rishi Agastya, Rishi Agastya & Nakkirar",
      "optionC":"Nakkirar,Rishi Agastya, Rishi Agastya",
      "optionD":"None of the above",
      "correctAns":"Rishi Agastya, Rishi Agastya & Nakkirar"
   },
   {
      "question":"Gandhar Kingdom of Later vedic phase was mostly located at which of the following places?",
      "optionA":"Afghanistan",
      "optionB":"Rawalpindi and Peshawar districts of Pakistan",
      "optionC":"Kashmir",
      "optionD":"Harappa",
      "correctAns":"Rawalpindi and Peshawar districts of Pakistan"
   },
   {
      "question":"Amarsimha whose work Amarkosha is related to which of the following ?",
      "optionA":"Poetry",
      "optionB":"Lexicography",
      "optionC":"Grammar",
      "optionD":"wars",
      "correctAns":"Lexicography"
   },
   {
      "question":"In which of the following Buddhist Councils , the compilation of Dhamma Pitaka and Sutta Pitaka took Place?",
      "optionA":"1st",
      "optionB":"2nd",
      "optionC":"3rd",
      "optionD":"4th",
      "correctAns":"1st"
   },
   {
      "question":"The first Buddhist Council was held at Rajagriha ________?",
      "optionA":"Shortly after Budhha’s Death",
      "optionB":"Shortly before Buddha’s Death",
      "optionC":"A century After Buddha’s Death",
      "optionD":"A century After Buddha’s Death",
      "correctAns":"Shortly after Budhha’s Death"
   },
   {
      "question":"Who among the following first postulated that 'All objects in the Physical Universe are reducible to a finite number of atoms'?",
      "optionA":"Maharishi Kapil",
      "optionB":"Maharishi Kanaad",
      "optionC":"Maharish Vyas",
      "optionD":"Maharishi Patanjali",
      "correctAns":"Maharishi Kanaad"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which among the following dynasty was founded by Vindyashakti?",
      "optionA":"Vakataka",
      "optionB":"Satvahana",
      "optionC":"Hoysala",
      "optionD":"Kadamaba",
      "correctAns":"Vakataka"
   },
   {
      "question":"Who among the following was behind the “epoch making” discovery of Arthashastra that altered the false perception of the European scholars that Ancient Indians learnt the art of administration from the Greeks?",
      "optionA":"R. Shamasastry",
      "optionB":"C. Sivarama Murti",
      "optionC":"K. S. Neelakantan Unni",
      "optionD":"Veturi Prabhakara Sastri",
      "correctAns":"R. Shamasastry"
   }
]